Silas Deane Papers
Connecticut Historical Society
- I. Correspondence: 1753 - 1795
  - Letters to and from Silas Deane., 3 Sept. 178.8 - 28 Oct. 1788; (6 items) (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Letters to and from Silas Deane., 19 Nov. 1788 - 26 Dec. 1788; (8 items) (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Letters to and from Silas Deane., 9 Jan. 1789 - 12 Aug. 1789; (11 items) (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Barnabas Deane to Theodore Hopkins on the death of Silas Deane., 25 Feb. 1790; (1 item) (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Letters from Robert Harris & Theodore Hopkins., 7 Jan. 1795 & 19 Feb 1795; (2 items) (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Letter book: 26 Aug. 1777 - 30 March 1778, (1 Volume) (Box 5, Folder 104)
    Mss note first leaf "One of Silas Deane's Letter books containing his correspondence from March 30 to August 23, 1777 was stolen from him by one Foulloy and sold to Jefferson for 25 louis for the account of the government. See Jefferson's Works, Vol ii, 454, 578, 582. The Secretary of State, May 8, 1876, wrote me that the book was not in the possession of that department" C.J.H. (Charles F. Hoadley).
  - Letter book: 8 April 1780 - 23 Oct. 1781, (1 Volume) (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Letter book: 21 Oct. 1781 - 2 April 1784, (1 Volume) (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Silas Deane Correspondence in other CHS collections: William Samuel Johnsonfrom the William Samuel Johnson Papers., 7 Feb. 1774 - 4 Aug. 1774; (4 items) (Box 6, Folder 107)
  - Silas Deane Correspondence (transcriptions) in other CHS collections: Richard Law from Ernst Law Papers., (2 items) (Box 6, Folder 108)
  - Silas Deane Correspondence in other CHS collections: Jonathan Trumbull from Jonathan Trumbull, Sr. Papers., 17 Aug. 1774 - 20 June 1775; (13 items) (Box 6, Folder 109)
  - Silas Deane Correspondence in other CHS collections: Joseph Trumbull from Joseph Trumbull Papers., 11 April 1774 - 7 Sept. 1775; (3 items) (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Silas Deane Correspondence in other CHS collections: Jeremiah Wadsworth from Jeremiah Wadsworth Papers., 12 Oct. 1778; (6 items) (Box 6, Folder 111)
  - Silas Deane Correspondence in other CHS collections: Jeremiah Wadsworth from Jeremiah Wadsworth Papers., 9 Feb. 1779, 21 June 1779, 20 July 1779; (6 items) (Box 6, Folder 112)
  - Silas Deane Correspondence in other CHS collections: Jeremiah Wadsworth from Jeremiah Wadsworth Papers., 23 April 1786; (2 items) (Box 6, Folder 113)
  - Silas Deane Correspondence in other CHS collections: Agreement with Sieur Du Coudray from Williams Papers., 11 Sept. 1776; (2 items) (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Transcriptions and translations of documents in English and French repositories - source unknown., 1776 - 1785; (12 items) (Box 6, Folder 115)
  - Silas Deane Correspondence in other CHS collections: Silas Deane to John Hancock, found in Vol.- 2 CHS Collections, Sept. 14, 1778; (2 items) (Box 6, Folder 116)
- II. Writings: 1772 - 1786
  - "Proposals", Aug. 1772; (6 items) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Silas Deane on Relief for Boston" (printed in Connecticut Courant)., 1774; (2 items) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "List of Delegates at Philadelphia.", Sept. 1774; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Petition of His Majesty.", Oct. 1774; (3 items) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Resolves Proposed 1774.", (3 items) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "A Plan for Making Discoveries, Purchases and Settlements on the Western Lands within the Limits of the Connecticut Charter" (photocopy)., 1774; (1 Volume) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Diary of Transactions in Congress, (fragments)., 1 - 6 Oct. 1774; (2 Volumes) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Circular letter from Lord Dartmouth., 3 March 1775; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Petition General Assembly New Haven., March 1775; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Petition to King (incomplete)., March 1775; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Proposals for a confederation of the Colonies., July 1775?; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Edict of Governor of Hispaniola., 16 Oct. 1775; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Extract minutes Congress: Resolution of the Appointment of Committee of Congress - written by Charles Thomson., (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Articles of Agreement Wethersfield Company of Independents., April 1775; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Proposal to General Assembly (incomplete) re taxing., 1775; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - "Essay uncompleted.", 1775; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - "Mémoire Infantry Regiment d'Aunis" March (in French)., 1776; (1 Volume) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "Mémoire" re resolution of independence, Congress, "presented to French minister on declamation of Independence 15 May, 1776"., May 15, 1776; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - "Mémoire" in relation to the commerce between Great Britain and Connecticut., 15 Aug. 1776; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - On Commence Between Great Britain and America., [179-?]; (9 items) (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - "Observations of Commerce" - note from Sir Robert Herries., 1783; (11 items) (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Ms. drafts "Observations respecting a navigable canal from Lake Champlain to the St. Lawrence., Oct. 25, 1785; (4 items) (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - "Additional Remarks" re canal Lake Champlain - drafts., 20 March 1787; (7 items) (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - "Additional Remarks" re canal Lake Champlain - St. Lawrence., April 1788; (4 items) (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Notes on canal Connecting Lake Champlain to St. Lawrence River., [17--?]; (9 items) (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - "Mémoire" on tobacco., March 24, 1779; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Drafts "Mémoire" on tobacco., 1786; (4 items) (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - On the making of salt., [17--?]; (4 items) (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - On the subject of sawing timber., [17--?]; (2 items) (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Descriptions of Mills or Explanation of Droughts., [17--?]; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Note on history of fruit and vegetable culture in Britain., [17--?]; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Essay: Justification U.S. seeking independence., [17--?]; (3 items) (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Observations on Gen. Gage's account of the affair at Lexington., [17--?]; (1 item) (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Essay on the policy of France toward the American colonies in the Revolutionary Era., [17--?]; (6 items) (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Notes and Statistics on Colonial trade with Great Britain., [17--?]; (2 items) (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - On post-revolutionary government in U.S., [17--?]; (4 items) (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Essay in form of letter re. post-revolutionary settlement and trade with Britain., [17--?]; (15 items) (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Draft "Mémoire" post-war commerce U.S. and Britain., [17--?]; (12 items) (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - "Loose and General Thoughts and Observations" on economy post-war U.S. and Britain., [17--?]; (12 items) (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Notes and statistics on trade Great Britain and U.S., [17--?]; (8 items) (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Drafts essay on post-war economic conditions Canada., [17--?]; (8 items) (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - "Chapter lst The Dignity of the Subject.", [17--?]; (4 items) (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Unidentified fragments, n.d. (letter from "Concord" with acrostic poems re Israel King) (Calculation compound interest) (note on inhabitants of Sheffield, 1615)., [17--?]; (6 items) (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Arthur Lee's Diaries., 1777 - 1779; (6 volumes) (Box 7, Folder 44)
- III. Business and Legal Papers: 1753 - 1788
  - Mss receipts and notes., 1753 - 1776; (5 items) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Contracts for ships masts and spars with France and Spain., 1775 - 1776; (12 items) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Contracts for ships masts and spars with France and Spain., 1778; (4 items) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Contracts for ships masts and spars with France and Spain., 1779 - 1780; (3 items) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Contracts masts British government., 1755; (4 items) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Contracts masts British government J. Ingersoll)., 1760; (3 items) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Contracts masts American government., 1775, 1776, 1780; (5 items) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Specifications, estimates, records wood cut for masts., [178-?]; (3 items) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Memos, receipts Gerard, Vergennes - Franey (gold box) Grand., [178-?]; (4 items) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Deeds: 1765 (land Colchester), 1779 (Ohio territory); copy contract for building of 3 story brick house, no place, no date., 1765 & 1779; (3 items) (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Elizabeth Deane to "Sammy" (Webb?) n.d. re sale carriage phaeton)., [17--?]; (1 item) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Orders on behalf Josiah Buck endorsed by Jesse Deane, 1784, 1786; claims on estate J. Buck due J. Deane, 1799., (5 items) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence family and business Simeon Deane., 1775 - 1781; (5 items) (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Cash book Simeon Deane, 1776; receipt Simeon Deane to Barnabas Deane 1777; account of sale of cloth for Simeon Deane, 1785., 1776, 1777 & 1781; (3 items) (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Journal of the most material transactions relating to the Ship Soucy from the time of her arrival in Virginia until she was destroyed in the Invasion of Portsmouth., 1779, Sept 1.; (1 Volume) (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Mss. map of Norfolk and Portsmouth, Va., 1779; (1 item) (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Plan of Pensacola Powder House., [179-?]; (1 item) (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - List of papers left with Simeon Deane, Williamsburg., May 29, 1780; (1 item) (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Inventory of the estate of Simeon Deane, Dec. 1788; deposition re will of Simeon Deane., (2 items) (Box 8, Folder 19)
- IV. Accounts: 1765 - 1781
  - Labels on packages of documents when received., [17--?]; (2 items) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Silas Deane's Summary of expenses while in Philadelphia on return from France; and receipts., 1778-80; (26 items) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Silas Deane's expenses and receipts., 1765-1777; (7 items) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Silas Deane's expenses in France and bill of goods, 1778; (4 items) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Silas Deane's expenses in France and America, 1779; (5 items) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Silas Deane's expenses in France, 1780; (33 items) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Silas Deane's expenses in France, 1781; (17 items) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Silas Deane's expenses in France and Ghent, 1781; (21 items) (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Silas Deane's expenses in Ghent, 1781; (39 items) (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Silas Deane's expenses in France and England, 1783; (11 items) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Silas Deane's expenses, [17--?]; (16 items) (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Accounts Edward Bancroft, Feb. 1778 - Aug. 1779; (2 items) (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Account Samuel Beale, [17--?]; (1 item) (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Accounts Le Roy de Chaumont, 1777, 1778, 1780 & 1786; (5 items) (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Accounts Jean Charles De Bay, 1781-82; (1 item) (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Accounts Haller Geradot - Co., 1776-1778; (8 items) (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Accounts Ferdinand Grand, 1777 & 1778; (7 items) (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Accounts Nicholas LaFarque, 1777-81; (15 items) (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Accounts Robert Morris, 1779; (1 item) (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Accounts Isaac Moses, 1778-79; (4 items) (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Accounts Roche and Bromfield, 1777-79; (17 items) (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Accounts Jonathan William, 1777-80; (2 items) (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Receipts money paid to French officers going to America, 1776-77 (includes Demauroy commission as Major-General, 1776; note from Pulaski), 1776 - 1777; (8 items) (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Receipts money paid to American officers in France, 1776-78; (19 items) (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Account book of Franklin, Deane and Adams., Dec. 1776 - June 1778; (1 Volume) (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Summary of account of money owed by Congress to Silas Deane (compiled by Silas Deane)., 1776 - 1780; (10 items) (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Writings: drafts essay on terms peace settlement Britain and America, [17--?]; (10 items) (Box OB 1, Folder 1)
  - Writings: articles of agreement of a privateer, (author unknown), 1740; (1 item) (Box OB 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Committee of Merchants, May 23, May 29, 1770; (2 items) (Box OB 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: convention landholders, merchants and inhabitants of Connecticut, Sept. 10, 1770; (1 item) (Box OB 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 14 Dec. 1775 Silas Deane from G. Saltonstall, (1 item) (Box OB 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 11 Aug. 1776, 12 Sept. 1776; (2 items) (Box OB 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1776; (2 items (1 Volume)) (Box OB 1, Folder 8)
  - Writings: "General State of my Demand on the United States", 29 May 1780; (1 item) (Box OB 1, Folder 9)
  - 13 Jan. 1776 Silas Deane to ED.; 23 Jan. 8 Feb. 1776 from G. Saltonstall: - March Farewell to ED., (4 items) (Box OB 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence (R. Morris), 28 Feb. 1777; 29 June 1777; (2 items) (Box OB 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: 1 June 1778 (C. Thomas); 3 July 1780; (R. Morris); I Jan. 1781 (J. Wilson), 1778 - 1781; (3 items) (Box OB 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: (Jonathan Trumbull); Letter from Jonathan Trumbull (missing), 15 May & 1 Nov. 1782; (5 items) (Box OB 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: (Thomas Barclay with remarks on accounts)., June 1784 - June 1785; (5 items) (Box OB 1, Folder 14)
- V. Memorials to congress: 1835
  - Correspondence to James H. Trumbull and Charles J. Hoadley re transmission of Memorial from the U.S. Dept. of the Treasury 1863, 1875. Table of contents of Memorial appended to letter of April 20, 1875., (6 items) (Box OB 2, Folder 1)
  - Printed copies Memorial of the Heirs of Silas Deane, Jan. 10, 1835. 3. Printed Reports Senate of the United States: 1841, 1842:, (4 items) (Box OB 2, Folder 2)
  - Two Printed Reports of Senate of the United States: 1. 26th Congress 2nd Session; 2. 27th Congress 2nd Session., 1841 - 1842; (2 volumes) (Box OB 2, Folder 3)
  - Fly leaves from "Silas Deane's Accounts"; copy pencilled note inside back cover, 1835; (3 items) (Box OB 2, Folder 4)
  - Copy of Commission of Captain granted by the king to Sieur Augustin Francois L'Epine Des-Epiniers. 15 Nov. 1776 (in French); found in these papers - not part of the Memorial; marked "A" on document and on Table of Contents, 1835; (1 item) (Box OB 2, Folder 5)
  - No. 1. Account United States against Silas Deane, Esq. As settled by Mr. Barclay (copied from the books of the Treasury Department)., 1777-1787; (1 Volume) (Box OB 2, Folder 6)
  - No. 2. Account against Mssrs. Delaps as settled by Mr. Barclay and attested by Register 1834-35. (This and the following copied from the books at the Treasury Dept.), 1834 - 1835; (2 items (1 Volume)) (Box OB 2, Folder 7)
  - No. 3. Account of Mon. Le Ray Chaumont as settled by Mr. Barclay, June 14, 1784; (2 items (1 Volume)) (Box OB 2, Folder 8)
  - No. 4. Caron de Beaumarchais account for military supplies and purchased by Silas Deane for the U. States., 1777-1793; (2 items (1 Volume)) (Box OB 2, Folder 9)
  - No. 5a. Accounts of Solieur, the Banker; b. Particulars of Grand's charge of 26,713 livres; C. Joint account of Franklin and Deane, 1777-1785; (2 items (1 Volume)) (Box OB 2, Folder 10)
  - No. 6a. Report of the Mr. Lee's Committee, Nov. 1783 sanctioning allowance of 5% commission on purchases etc.: b. Correspondence of Committee and Robert Morris; C. Copy of contract with Secret Committee; d. Copy of instructions to Silas Deane; e. Other documents accompanying Mr. Lee's report, (7 items) (Box OB 2, Folder 11)
  - No. 7. Mr. Deane's accounts with Mr. Barclay's observations upon them as transmitted to Robert Morris, for his instructions, as laid before Congress by Mr. Morris; Deane's letter to Barclay 23 March 1782; Barclay's letter to Morris 8 June 1784; Morris' letter to Congress 30 Sept. 1784, 1782 - 1784; (7 items) (Box OB 2, Folder 12)
  - No. 8. Mr. Deane's accounts and accounts current stated by himself (Copies in part of those transmitted by Barclay to Morris), 1776-1778; (10 items) (Box OB 2, Folder 13)
  - No. 9. Abstracts of daily expenses, 1776-1781; (16 items) (Box OB 2, Folder 14)
  - No. 10. Accounts of household expenses; household furniture left with Dr. Franklin; expenses of couriers to Versailles; expense of postage. None of which were credited to Mr. Deane in Settlement., 1776-1778; (4 items) (Box OB 2, Folder 15)
  - No. 11a Original agreement with Baron de Kalb and Viscount de Mauroy - showing that the two bills on Delaps charged to Mr. Deane were drawn in payment of said contracts. llb. Original agreement with Viscomte de Mauroy., 1776; (1 item) (Box OB 2, Folder 16)
  - Original agreement with Lafayette, 1776; (1 item) (Box OB 2, Folder 17)
  - Photocopies Lafayette, de Mauroy. and de Kalb agreements; 2 off print articles re the agreement; 2 labels, [179-]; (3 items) (Box OB 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence Robert Morris to Silas Deane, March 1, 10, 30, 1776; (4 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence Robert Morris to Silas Deane, June 5, 6 1776; (3 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence Robert Morris to Silas Deane No. 12 August 11, 1776; Sept. 12, 1776; label from bound volume: "re trade in indigo and rice in the Delaps account", (5 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence Robert Morris to Silas Deane, Oct. 4, Dec. 4, 1776; (3 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence Robert Morris to Thomas Morris Jan. 31, 1777 (signed copy), to John Ross Jan. 31, 1777 (signed copy), to Commissioners Franklin, Deane, and Lee Feb. 18, 1777, to Silas Deane Feb. 27, 1777, (5 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence Robert Morris to Silas Deane, June 29, 1777; (4 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence Robert Morris from Lesieur Chaumont, Jan. 7, 1777, to Thomas Bromfield, May 20, 1777 (copy not signed), (2 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence Robert Morris to Silas Deane, June 7, 1871; (1 item) (Box OB 3, Folder 26)
  - No. 13 signed copies Ls Silas Deane to Robert Morris, 1776 - 1783; (10 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 27)
  - No. 14 AlS B. Franklin to Silas Deane, 1776 - 1783; (4 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 28)
  - No. 15 (copies from Silas Deane's Letter book) Silas Deane to Benjamin Franklin, 1782; (8 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 29)
  - No. 16 (copies from-Silas Deane's Letter books) Silas Deane to Thomas Barclay, 1782 - 1783; (11 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 30)
  - No. 17 (copies from Silas Deane's Letter books) Silas Deane to John Jay, 1782 - 1783; (3 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 31)
  - No. 18 ALsS Caron De Beaumarchais to Silas Deane, 1776-1778; (13 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 32)
  - No. 18a Translations AlsS C. De Beaumarchais to Silas Deane, 1776-1778; (12 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 33)
  - No. 19 Marine committee Continental Congress to Silas Deane directing him to procure and fit out a naval force Nov. 7, 1775; ALS from Stephen Hopkins, Chairman, to Silas Deane Nov. 16, 1775, (2 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 34)
  - No. 19a An Estimate for the Expense of a Ship of War with the original rough draft of Rules and Regulations for the government of the Navy., Oct. 1775; (3 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 35)
  - No. 20. Committee of Congress for Secret Correspondence to Silas Deane appointment as agent to France., March 2, 1776; (1 item) (Box OB 3, Folder 36)
  - No. 20a Continental Congress appointment Benjamin Franklin, Silas Deane and Arthur Lee to Court of France. (signed) John Hancock., Oct. 23, 1776; (1 item) (Box OB 3, Folder 37)
  - No. 21 (copies from Vol. I Sparks Diplomatic Correspondence) Benjamin Franklin to President of Congress March 21, 1778; Compte de Vergennes to President of Congress (translation) March 25, 1778; Compte de Vergennes to Silas Deane March 26, 1778., (3 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 38)
  - No. 22a ALS Silas Deane to Carmichael (copy by Silas Deane sent to Barclay)., June 30, 1784; (1 item) (Box OB 3, Folder 39)
  - No. 22b ALS Thomas Barclay to Silas Deane., July 7, 1784; (1 item) (Box OB 3, Folder 40)
  - No. 22c - d (copy) Silas Deane to Baldwin, the Printer; ALS H. Baldwin to Silas Deane., 1783; (2 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 41)
  - No. 22e (copy by Deane) ALS Silas Deane to J. Debrett., Aug. 8, 1783; (1 item) (Box OB 3, Folder 42)
  - No. 22 American Mercury Mon. re. death of Silas Deane., Dec. 28, 1789; (1 item) (Box OB 3, Folder 43)
  - No. 22f "Testimony showing the weakness and imbecility in body and mind of Jesse Deane, only son of Silas Deane.", Dec. 5, 1835; (5 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 44)
  - No. 23 Affidavit Horatio Alden., Feb. 29, 1836; (3 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 45)
  - Mss draft Memorial to Congress (by Samuel Burche?)., [1835?]; (3 volumes) (Box OB 3, Folder 46)
  - Mss copy Memorial to Congress; original from which Memorial printed by Blair and Gives., Jan. 1835; (29 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 47)
  - Mss draft with corrections of Silas Deane's accounts prepared for Congress by the Fifth Auditor., 1838 - 1842; (9 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 48)
  - Mss copy statement of the accounts of Silas Deane., [179-?]; (1 volume) (Box OB 3, Folder 49)
  - Mss copy "A list of vouchers supporting the claim of Silas Deane's heirs on the United States.", 1842; (1 Volume) (Box OB 3, Folder 50)
  - Mss corrections of Mr. Barclay's statement of Mr. Deane's accounts., [1835?]; (2 items) (Box OB 3, Folder 51)
  - Ms copy contract John Alsop Francis Lewis and Philip Livingston, - and Silas Deane and Robert Morris and the Committee of Secrecy 1775; Certified copy 1842., (1 item) (Box OB 3, Folder 52)
  - Printed copy memorial with ms note "Drawn up by Samuel Hurons?) agent for the claimants"., [17--?]; (1 Volume) (Box OB 3, Folder 53)
  - Printed copy H.R. No. 952 Silas Deane; Senate 201 1841., 1842; (1 Volume) (Box OB 3, Folder 54)
- VI. Barnabas Deane: 1768 - 1792
  - Correspondence, 1768 - 1775; (4 items) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (John Hancock; Jeremiah Wadsworth), 2 Nov. 1776 - 7 June 1776; (10 items) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (John Hancock), 1 June 1776 - 15 Nov. 1777; (10 items) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 19 Nov. 1777 - 27 Oct. 1780; (9 items) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (B. Tallmadge), 19 Feb. 1781 - 13 May 1783; (12 items) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (Jeremiah Wadsworth)., 25 July 1783 - 14 Feb. 1785; (10 items) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 30 June 1785 - 18 June 1789; (10 items) (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence., 1790 - 1815; (13 items) (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Ship Trumbull Papers., 1776 - 1792; (45 items) (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Misc. business and legal papers., 1776 - 1792; (95 items) (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Code books., 1780; (2 items (volumes)) (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Copy order of limitation estate Simeon Deane; copy General Account and settlement estate Barnabas Deane. Jeremiah Wadsworth, Executor., 22 Feb. 1792; (4 items) (Box 11, Folder 12)